A Guide to the Papers of Maud Carter Clement, 1756-1968
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Maud Carter Clement 1756-1968
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9479
This collection consists of ca. 2000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of Rutledge C. Clement and Henry T. Clement of Danville, Va. and Chatham, Va., 1970 May 8.
Biographical/Historical Information
Maud Carter Clement was a writer and historian of southwestern Virginia.
Scope and Content
Genealogical information and local history of Pittsylvania County, Va. are the main interests of the collection of Mrs. Clement, a southwest Virginia historian and writer. Correspondence, articles, speeches, garden club material, and memorabilia are also included. The collection contains surveyors maps of southwest Virginia and an extract of a 1795 diary of Marsha D. Blodgett.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Material
Six boxes of official records of the Pittsylvania County Court (originally boxes 3-8) were transferred to the Library of Virginia in October, 1975.
Contents List
- Series I: Research Materials
  - Signature of Peter Jefferson, Original and photocopy, March 19, 1756 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Account Sheet of John Smith, Jr., January 1, 1763, DS. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Fragment of Virginia Gazette, July 31, 1778, 4 page fragment. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Revolutionary War order by Major Abra. Shelton, May 23, 1781, DS. (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Fragment Virginia and North Carolina Almanac for 1803, 1802 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Anselm Lynch to Ralph Smith, April 26, 1811, ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
  - George Morrison to Mrs. Elizabeth Royal, November 3, 1837, ALS. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Advertisement of a High School for Ladies, May 17, 1855 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - D. T. Williams to B. W. Morrison, August 14, 1857, ALS. (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Newspaper clipping, Obituary of Emily W. Buford, November 1859 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Envelope addressed to Miss Millie Morrison, ca. 1860 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Bond of W. B. Wright for military equipment, 1861, DS. (Box-folder 1:12)
  - [empty] (Box-folder 1:13)
  - William E. Meade tobacco sales receipt, May 31, 1867 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Tobacco sales receipts, 1868-1869, 2 DS. (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Three General Accounts receipts, 1869-1873, 3 DS. (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Tobacco market report- Richmond, Va., August 22, 1869 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Betty J. Clark to Chatham Baptist Church, March 7, 1879, ALS. (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Stock certificate of L. H. Pigg, May 1, 1886, DS. (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Copy of letter- Prudence Hairston to Eliza G. Calloway, [1888?] (Box-folder 1:20)
- Series II: Pocket Plantation Papers
  - Rough notes on the Smith family of Pocket Plantation,n.d., Ms. ca. 125 pp. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Draft of The Pocket Plantation,n.d., AMsS, 130 pp. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - The Tobacco Lords of Glasgow and The Virginia Planter- As Shown by the Pocket Papers, 1763-1775, n.d., TMsS, 100 pp. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Copy of The Pocket Land Grant from Surveyor's Records, Pittsylvania County, n.d., Ms. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Account of John Smith and Pocket Plantation, n.d., 3 items, 144 pp. (28 photostats, 37 typed manuscripts, 77 ms.) (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Illustrations and pictures for The Pocket: An 'Old Belt' Tobacco Plantation,n.d., 10 items. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Notes re: the Pocket Lands and Smith Family, n.d., Ms. 33 pp. (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Captain R. Orme to Governor Dinwiddie [1775?], n.d., 13 items: 1 contura copy, 5 photostats, 7 typed manuscripts. (Box-folder 2:8)
  - George Washington to Governor Dinwiddie, n.d., 15 items. (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Photostats of letters to Mr. John Smith of The Pocket Plantation, 1960, 7 items. (Box-folder 2:10)
- Series III: Genealogy
  - Genealogical notes re: Adams, n.d., AMsS, 28 pp. (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Ayers, February 22, 1955, Ms. (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Genealogical data re: Barksdale-Womack-White, n.d., AMsS. (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Genealogical data re: John Bates, n.d., AMsS. (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Genealogical data and correspondence re: Bay[e]s, 1954, 23 pp. (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Genealogical correspondence re: Bennett-Duncan, May 14, 1950, 4 pp. (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Brauson, April 4, 1954, 10 pp. (2 items). (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Buford [Beauford], April 14, 1955, 16 pp. (3 items) (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Sara Belle Ashby to Maud C. Clement re: Cabaniss, March 28, 1932, ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Calioway, James and William, 1930-1962, 23 pp. (Box-folder 9:10)
  - M. W. Hawley to Maud C. Clement re: Theodrick Carter, March 22, 1916 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Thomas Carter and related families, 1909-1960, 35 pp. (20 items). (Box-folder 9:12)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Choat[e], March 22, 1954, 2 items. (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: William Clark, August 7, 1963, 5 items. (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Clements, Kentucky branch, July 6, 1930, 6 items (Box-folder 9:15)
  - Genealogical notes re: Clift, n.d. (Box-folder 9:16)
  - Genealogical data re: Isaac Coles, Sr., June 18, 1928 (Box-folder 9:17)
  - Major Edward Dale: 1655-1694 by J. L. Miller, n.d., TMsS, 6 pp. (Box-folder 9:18)
  - Genealogical data re: Dalton-Mustain, 1954, 4 items. (Box-folder 9:19)
  - Genealogical notes re: Thomas Davis, n.d. (Box-folder 9:20)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Devlin, 1931-1945, 12 items. (Box-folder 9:21)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Dillard, ca. 1945-1952, 8 items. (Box-folder 9:22)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: John Dix, 1954-1955, 5 items. (Box-folder 9:23)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Dodson-Henry, 1948-1952, 31 items. (Box-folder 9:24)
  - Genealogy: Donelson-Davis-Stockley, n.d., AMsS. (Box-folder 9:25)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Donelson and related families, 1905-1950, 24 items. (Box-folder 9:26)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Benjamin Duncan, 1928, 5 items. (Box-folder 9:28)
  - Genealogical data re: Bryant Easley, n.d. (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Thomas East, 1924-1925, 4 items. (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Genealogical data re: Echols-Clement, April 12, 1954 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Genealogical data re: Estes, n.d. (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Evans-Hampton, November 10, 1955, 2 items. (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Fontaine-Carter, 1929, 5 items. (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Fullenlove-Vance, October 20, 1930, 4 items. (Box-folder 10:7)
  - Genealogical notes re: Fulton, n.d. (Box-folder 10:8)
  - Genealogical notes re: Gammon, n.d. (Box-folder 10:9)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Gilbert, August 11, 1952, 2 items. (Box-folder 10:10)
  - Genealogical notes re: Giles, n.d. (Box-folder 10:11)
  - Genealogical notes re: Glass-Johnson-Gilliam, n.d. (Box-folder 10:12)
  - Genealogical notes re: Glenn, February 14, 1931, 2 items. (Box-folder 10:13)
  - Genealogical notes re: Gravely, n.d. (Box-folder 10:14)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Gwin, April 1, 1931, 3 items. (Box-folder 10:15)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Hall, 1953-1954, 8 items. (Box-folder 10:16)
  - Genealogical notes- The Hallom Family of Essex, England and of Virginia,n.d., 4 pp. (Box-folder 10:17)
  - Genealogical notes re: Hamilton-Mabry, n.d. (Box-folder 10:18)
  - Genealogical notes re: Hankins, n.d. (Box-folder 10:19)
  - Genealogical notes re: Harden, n.d. (Box-folder 10:20)
  - Genealogical chart re: Benjamin Harrison, n.d. (Box-folder 10:21)
  - Genealogical notes re: Harrison, n.d. (Box-folder 10:22)
  - Genealogical notes re: Ainsworth-Harrison, March 21, 1929 (Box-folder 10:23)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Harbour-Dalton, April 8, 1924, 2 items. (Box-folder 10:24)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Thomas Hill, 1931-1956, 6 items. (Box-folder 10:25)
  - Genealogical data re: Hobson-McBride, May 14, 1959, 3 items. (Box-folder 10:26)
  - Genealogical notes re: Hunt, February 7, 1931, 4 items. (Box-folder 10:27)
  - Genealogical notes re: Hurt-Cox-Clark, n.d. (Box-folder 10:28)
  - A. Cloyd Gill to Maud Clement re: Hutching, September 1, 1941, TLS. (Box-folder 10:29)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Hutchinson-Linthicum, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 4 items.)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: James Innes, 1963-1965, 3 items. (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Genealogical notes: Blanks James, n.d. (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Genealogical notes re: James and Haynes, n.d. (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Genealogy of John Johns, May 27, 1935, 6 items. (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Samuel Jones, 1955, 3 items. (Box-folder 11:5)
  - Genealogical data re: Jones, 1934 (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Keele-Hughes, July 29, 1954, 2 items. (Box-folder 11:7)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Keen, 1929, 5 items. (Box-folder 11:8)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Lane, 1925, 4 items. (Box-folder 11:9)
  - Genealogical data re: Lane-Cloud, January 16, 1918 (Box-folder 11:10)
  - Genealogical chart of John Lanier, 1951 (Box-folder 11:11)
  - Genealogical correspondence re: Lanier, n.d., 42 items. (Box-folder 11:12)
  - Genealogical data re: Lanier of London, January 30, 1956, 2 items. (Box-folder 11:13)
  - Ms. Lanier... n.d. (Box-folder 11:14)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Charles Lay, October 15, 1954, 2 items. (Box-folder 11:15)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Thomas Leek, December 3, 1953, 2 items. (Box-folder 11:16)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Leftwich Forest Home, 1929-1958, 8 items. (Box-folder 11:17)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Lewis, 1929-1945, 4 items. (Box-folder 11:18)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Loyless-Harden, 1955, 4 items. (Box-folder 11:19)
  - Genealogical notes re: Luck, 1957-1958, 2 items. (Box-folder 11:20)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Lumpkin, 1911-1930, 9 items. (Box-folder 11:21)
  - Genealogical data re: McCraw-Scales, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Genealogical notes re: McCubbin-Lane, n.d. (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Genealogical notes re: McGehee, February 8, 1931 (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Genealogical data re: Madison-Garrett, 1933, 3 items. (Box-folder 12:4)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Mahan, 1926, 5 items. (Box-folder 12:5)
  - Genealogical data re: Maples, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 12:6)
  - Genealogical notes re: Merritt, n.d. (Box-folder 12:7)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: James Monroe, Andrew Jackson and Rachel Donelson Jackson, 1929, 2 items. (Box-folder 12:8)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Blanks Moody, March 6, 1929, 3 items. (Box-folder 12:9)
  - Genealogical notes re: Moore, n.d. (Box-folder 12:10)
  - Genealogical data re: Joseph Morton, n.d. (Box-folder 12:11)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Morton, 1929, 4 items. (Box-folder 12:12)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Motley-Hodges, ca. 1936-1941, 18 items. (Box-folder 12:13)
  - Genealogical data and correspondence re: Mustain-Waller, 1951-1952, 4 items. (Box-folder 12:14)
  - Genealogical notes re: Payne, Allen, Aikon-Wade-Terry, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 12:15)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Penick-Ferguson, 1950, 10 items. (Box-folder 12:16)
  - Genealogical data re: Daniel Price, July 12, 1950 (Box-folder 12:17)
  - Genealogical data re: James Perkins, 1951-1953, 2 items. (Box-folder 12:18)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Perkins-Pryor, 1906-1954, 4 items. (Box-folder 12:19)
  - Genealogical notes re: Phifer, 1930-1931, 4 items. (Box-folder 12:20)
  - Genealogical data re: Christian Poindexter, n.d. (Box-folder 12:21)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Prewitt-Pruitt-Prewett, September 16, 1931, 3 items. (Box-folder 12:22)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Price, 1930-1936, 7 items. (Box-folder 12:23)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Reynolds, 1941-1944, 4 items. (Box-folder 12:24)
  - Genealogical data re: Rice-Stone, n.d. (Box-folder 12:25)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Rice-Walden-Walling, September 12, 1965, 5 items. (Box-folder 12:26)
  - Genealogical notes re: Amos Richardson, n.d. (Box-folder 12:27)
  - Genealogical notes re: Robertson, n.d. (Box-folder 12:28)
  - Genealogical data re: Ro[h]rer, April 6, 1951 (Box-folder 12:29)
  - Louise Ingersoll to Maud Clement re: Lemuel Lanier, 1949-1956, 22 ALS. (Box-folder 13:1)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Scott-Coleman, February 5, 1933, 2 items. (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Shelton, 1914-1954, 20 items. (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Genealogical data re: Shields, October 25, 1933, 3 items. (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Short, March 3, 1955, 2 items. (Box-folder 13:5)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Shorter-Wyatt, 1930-1941, 18 items. (Box-folder 13:6)
  - Genealogical data re: Ignatius Simm, July 31, 1929 (Box-folder 13:7)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: James Simms, May 7, 1926, 2 items. (Box-folder 13:8)
  - Genealogical notes re: Simms of Henry County, n.d. (Box-folder 13:9)
  - Genealogical data re: Skaggs, December 9, 1938 (Box-folder 13:10)
  - Genealogical data re: Booker Smith, 1922, 2 Als. (Box-folder 13:11)
  - Genealogical data re: Byrd Smith, January 28, 1931 (Box-folder 13:12)
  - Genealogical notes: John Smith of Sandy River, n.d. (Box-folder 13:13)
  - Genealogy: Captain Thomas Smith's Family, n.d. (Box-folder 13:14)
  - Genealogical data re: Barton Stone, 1929 (Box-folder 13:15)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Stone-Hart, March 1, 1931, 4 items. (Box-folder 13:16)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: William-Swanson, November 12, 1934 (Box-folder 13:17)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Tunstai, n.d., 11 items. (Box-folder 13:18)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Talbot, March 27, 1931, 2 items. (Box-folder 13:19)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Terry, 1917-1956, 14 items. (Box-folder 13:20)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Thomas, 1930-1939, 5 items. (Box-folder 13:21)
  - Genealogical notes re: Thornton, February 3, 1932 (Box-folder 13:22)
  - Genealogical data re: Richard Thurman, January 13, 1953 (Box-folder 13:23)
  - Genealogical notes re: Townes, n.d. (Box-folder 13:24)
  - Genealogical data re: Treadway, January 16, 1965 (Box-folder 13:25)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Tunstall-Perkins, 1926-1933, 11 items. (Box-folder 13:26)
  - Genealogical notes re: Turner, n.d. (Box-folder 13:27)
  - Genealogical notes re: Walters, n.d. (Box-folder 14:1)
  - Genealogical notes re: Walton, n.d. (Box-folder 14:2)
  - Genealogical notes re: Ware-Harrison, n.d. (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Genealogy of George Washington, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 14:4)
  - Genealogical data re: Watkins, August 17, 1959 (Box-folder 14:5)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: John Watson, May 22, 1951, 3 items. (Box-folder 14:6)
  - Genealogical data re: Thomas Watson, March 8, 1928 (Box-folder 14:7)
  - Genealogical data re: White-Martin, n.d. (Box-folder 14:8)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Robert Williams, 1930-1931, 10 items. (Box-folder 14:9)
  - Genealogical data re: William Williams, June 27, 1953, 2 items. (Box-folder 14:10)
  - Genealogical notebook re: William Wilmer, n.d., ca. 12 pp. (Box-folder 14:11)
  - Genealogical data re: Wilson, 1929 (Box-folder 14:12)
  - Genealogical data re: Wimbish, March 7, 1931 (Box-folder 14:13)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Witcher, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 14:14)
  - Genealogical notes and correspondence re: Wooding, May 29, 1926 (Box-folder 14:15)
  - Genealogical notes re: Wright, n.d. (Box-folder 14:16)
  - General genealogical notes, n.d., 16 pp. (Box-folder 14:17)
  - Genealogical notebook, n.d., 50 pp. (Box-folder 14:18)
  - Genealogical notebook, n.d., 50 pp. (Box-folder 14:19)
- Series IV: Family Correspondence
  - [Sam?] Smith to Stella I. Clement, December 3, 1830, ALS. (Box-folder 15:1)
  - John T. Cole to George W. Clement, May 16, 1849, ALS. (Box-folder 15:2)
  - Jubal A. Early to James R. Clement, September 8, 1854, ALS. (Box-folder 15:3)
  - Bond of James R. Clement to George W. Clement, September 6, 1855, DS. (Box-folder 15:4)
  - Mary W. Walton to Mary J. Lanier, April 3, 185[7,9], Typescript. (Box-folder 15:5)
  - James Carter to Lucy Lanier Carter, 1862, ALS, with copy. (Box-folder 15:6)
  - Henry C. Clement to Harriet Morrison, December 3, 1863, ALS. (Box-folder 15:7)
  - Receipt of H. Dillard to Charles J. Clement, September 2, 1867, DS. (Box-folder 15:8)
  - Eliza G. P. Carter to Mary T. Johnson, February 17, 1870, Handwritten copy. (Box-folder 15:9)
  - Henry Pigg to Bettie Pigg, September 17, 1871 (Box-folder 15:10)
  - Ada B. Carter to James Carter, April 18, 1872, ALS. (Box-folder 15:11)
  - Miss Tinsley to S. F. Clement, June 25, 1872, ALS (Box-folder 15:12)
  - Sally P. Brown to Eliza G. P. Carter, April 22, 1892, Handwritten copy. (Box-folder 15:13)
  - Report cards-(2) of Maud Carter, 1895, DS. (Box-folder 15:14)
  - E. A. Barber to James Carter, April 13, 1909, TLS. (Box-folder 15:15)
  - S. F. Clement to Maud C. Clement, November 30, 1909, ALS. (Box-folder 15:16)
  - Maud Carter to Nathaniel Clement, 1909, 9 ALS. (Box-folder 15:17)
  - John W. Daniel to S. Fletcher Clement, February 2, 1910, TLS. (Box-folder 15:18)
  - John W. Williams to S. F. Clement, June 10, 1910, Telegram. (Box-folder 15:19)
  - C. O. Pruden to Maud C. Clement, March 24, 1916 (Box-folder 15:20)
  - Beffie to Maud C. Clement, 1927, 3 ALS. (Box-folder 15:21)
  - Bank statement for Elizabeth L. Clement, 1927, DS. (Box-folder 15:22)
  - 3 Newspaper Clippings re: Death of Elizabeth L. Clement, 1927 (Box-folder 15:23)
  - Card, Harry and Rutledge to Maud C. Clement, 1930 (Box-folder 15:24)
  - Stephen P. Clement to Maud C. Clement, April 13, 1933, ALS. (Box-folder 15:25)
  - Jennie Pollock Rose to Maud C. Clement, March 1, 1943 (Box-folder 15:26)
  - Florence Stulz to Maud C. Clement, January 4, 1945, ALS. (Box-folder 15:27)
  - Mary Carter Loner to Maud C. Clement, October 11, 1955, ALS. (Box-folder 15:28)
  - Henry P. Carter to Maud C. Clement, December 10, 1955, TLS. (Box-folder 15:29)
  - Henry P. Carter to Maud C. Clement, June 27, 1956, TLS. (Box-folder 15:30)
  - Macon Clement to Maud C. Clement, March 18, 1957, ALS. (Box-folder 15:31)
  - Stephen Clement to Maud C. Clement, Decemeber 30, 1959 (Box-folder 15:32)
  - An Ode to Grandma by Ann Macon Clement, 1959, AMsS. (Box-folder 15:33)
  - Family snapshot, August 1961 (Box-folder 15:34)
  - Whittington W. Clement to Maud C. Clement, September 27, 1962, ALS. (Box-folder 15:35)
  - Stephen Clement to Maud C. Clement, December 19, 1962, TLS. (Box-folder 15:36)
  - Birth record of the children of James and Lucy Lanier Carter, n.d. (Box-folder 15:37)
  - Elizabeth L. Clement to Maud C. Clement, n.d., 10 items. (Box-folder 15:38)
  - Photograph of [Maud Carter] while a student at Chatham Institute, [1895?] (Box-folder 15:39)
  - Elizabeth L. Clement to Elizabeth Stoneman, n.d., 3 ALS. (Box-folder 15:40)
  - Macon Clement to Maud C. Clement, n.d., Signed card. (Box-folder 15:41)
  - Preston to Macon Clement, December 21, ALS. (Box-folder 15:42)
  - Newspaper clippings re: Maud C. Clement, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 15:43)
  - Newspaper clippings re: Clement family, n.d. (Box-folder 15 items.)
- Series V: Correspondence-General
  - Juliet Fauntleroy to Maud C. Clement, August 18, 1906, ALS. (Box-folder 16:1)
  - Juliet Fauntleroy to Maud C. Clement, January 8, 1910, ALS. (Box-folder 16:2)
  - Joseph L. Miller to Maud C. Clement, January 15, 1910, ALS. (Box-folder 16:3)
  - L. Stillwell to Maud C. Clement, April 19, 1910, TLS/DS. (Box-folder 16:4)
  - C. B. Bryant to Maud C. Clement, May 3, 1913, ALS. (Box-folder 16:5)
  - Maud C. Clement to U. D. C., 1915, TLS. (Box-folder 16:6)
  - Jenny Nelson to Maud C. Clement, June 8, 1916, ALS. (Box-folder 16:7)
  - J. C. Fitzpatrick to Maud C. Clement, 1918, 2 TLS. (Box-folder 16:8)
  - J. M. Hooker to Maud C. Clement, December 11, 1923, TLS. (Box-folder 16:9)
  - Herbert Hoover to Maud C. Clement, January 31, 1924, TLS. (Box-folder 16:10)
  - William G. Stanard to Maud C. Clement, March 28, 1928, ALS. (Box-folder 16:11)
  - Anne French Conway to Maud C. Clement, June 28, 1929, ALS. (Box-folder 16:12)
  - A. B. Carrington to Maud C. Clement, July 7, 1931, TLS. (Box-folder 16:13)
  - Arthur C. Thompson to Maud C. Clement, October 23, 1933, TLS. (Box-folder 16:14)
  - J. D. Eggleston to Maud C. Clement, October 2, 1933, TLS. (Box-folder 16:15)
  - Elise Lanier to Maud C. Clement, 1935-1939, 6 letters. (Box-folder 16:16)
  - Ophelia Carr to Maud C. Clement, May 31, 1936, ALS. (Box-folder 16:17)
  - C. B. Wilmer to Maud C. Clement, May 31, 1936, ALS. (Box-folder 16:18)
  - Don P. Hasley to Maud C. Clement, October 20, 1936, TLS. (Box-folder 16:19)
  - T. G. Burch to Maud C. Clement, November 17, 1936, TLS. (Box-folder 16:20)
  - Harriet Fitzgerald to Maud C. Clement, [1936?], ALS. (Box-folder 16:21)
  - Pearl S. Buck to Maud C. Clement, January 1937, 2 TLS. (Box-folder 16:22)
  - E. G. Swem to Maud C. Clement, April 1, 1938, TLS. (Box-folder 16:23)
  - Dona Neil Raymond to Maud C. Clement, September 16, 1938, ALS. (Box-folder 16:24)
  - Dona Neil Raymond to Maud C. Clement, June 28, 1939, ALS. (Box-folder 16:25)
  - Mrs. J. T. Harris to Maud C. Clement, September 21, 1939, ALS. (Box-folder 16:26)
  - Sally W. Crawford to Maud C. Clement, April 27, 1941, ALS. (Box-folder 16:27)
  - Lucy W. Poindexter to Maud C. Clement, May 2, 1944, ALS. (Box-folder 16:28)
  - Norvell E. Wicker to Maud C. Clement, May 4, 1944, TLS. (Box-folder 16:29)
  - Bess Coleman to Maud C. Clement, May 13, 1944, ALS. (Box-folder 16:30)
  - N. E. Wicker to Maud C. Clement, September 16, 1944, TLS. (Box-folder 16:31)
  - R. J. Reid to Maud C. Clement, November 16, 1944, ALS. (Box-folder 16:32)
  - Mrs. Cleveland Dodge to Maud C. Clement, July 9, 1945, ALS. (Box-folder 16:33)
  - Lewis C. Williams to Maud C. Clement, January 28, 1947, TLS. (Box-folder 16:34)
  - Frederick J. Warnecke to Maud C. Clement, February 3, 1947, TLS. (Box-folder 16:35)
  - Adrienne Caliborne to Maud C. Clement, September 16, 1947, ALS. (Box-folder 16:36)
  - The Rt. Reverand William A. Brown to Maud C. Clement, September 1947, 2 TLS. (Box-folder 16:37)
  - Ida M. Valentine to Maud C. Clement, October 18, 1948, TLS. (Box-folder 16:38)
  - Elizabeth D. Reynolds to Maud C. Clement, February 3, 1949, ALS. (Box-folder 16:39)
  - J. D. Eggleston to Maud C. Clement, September 1949, 3 ALS. (Box-folder 16:40)
  - Lottie F. Dodson to Maud C. Clement, October 4, 1949, ALS. (Box-folder 16:41)
  - Bernard Baruch to Maud C. Clement, October 4, 1949, TLS. (Box-folder 16:42)
  - Dixon Wecter to Maud C. Clement, October 4, 1949, 2 TLS. (Box-folder 16:43)
  - Francis L. Berkeley to Maud C. Clement, April 26, 1952 (Box-folder 16:44)
  - John I. Dillard to Maud C. Clement, March 27, 1953, TLS. (Box-folder 16:45)
  - Captain W. W. Gilmer to Maud C. Clement, April 5, 1953, ALS. (Box-folder 16:46)
  - Kenneth J. Herzig to Maud C. Clement, April 6, 1953, TLS. (Box-folder 16:47)
  - G. MacLauren Brydon to Maud C. Clement, April 1953, 2 TLS. (Box-folder 16:48)